<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tales from the Field on Wsl Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/tales-from-the-field/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tales from the Field on Wsl Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tales-from-the-field/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shed</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-07-26-theshed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-07-26-theshed/</guid>
      <description>Since this blog now exists I thought I would share one of my favorite old stories, and possibly one of the stranger encounters I&amp;rsquo;ve had. A good alternative title for this story would be &amp;ldquo;Out of the hole and facing rebirth&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
One of my favorite things about this job is completing service requests - these are generally requests from people who actually want to see us. A nice change of pace from being the bearer of usually unpleasant news. Most of these requests are pretty routine - &amp;ldquo;person concerned about tree in proximity to power lines&amp;rdquo; is by far the most common. On this particular request, a neighbor was concerned about a property behind hers with a large tree growing into high voltage lines. Nothing strange, but not on her property. I called the person who made the request before heading out to see if I could get some more details and get access to her yard to see things from her vantage point. She agreed to meet and let me into her backyard, where I could access an easement and see the tree.
It was during monsoon season, the weather outside was nice and humid - the air still fresh from a recent rain, and the sky grey and overcast. The request was in one of my favorite central Phoenix neighborhoods with lots of dense old trees and flood irrigation. As soon as I pulled up in front of her property I could see the tree she was concerned about, a massive old female carob growing directly into the lines. I drove around to the other street to go talk to the property owners and schedule pruning access.
The property where the tree was located was entirely walled off, easily 10&amp;rsquo; tall wooden walls surrounding it. It looked vacant or abandoned. I couldn’t find a single access point to knock on the door, and my knocks and hollering at the front wall yielded nothing from the property - just confused looks from an elderly neighbor who was watering her plants next door.
I returned to the lady&amp;rsquo;s property who called the request, and decided to see if we had access to the tree through the easement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>