<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on Wsl Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on Wsl Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 19:18:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Commenting System with Staticman!</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-11-15-commenting-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 19:18:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-11-15-commenting-system/</guid>
      <description>The one bad thing about hosting a static blog is that implementing comments means you:
 Outsource, letting some other site handle it (like Disqus) Come up with some sort of crazy contraption to force a comment system into a static blog Spend hours scouring the internet to see what other people have done.  Obviously, outsourcing wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option - Disqus looks nice and all, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it would be fine for a lot of people, but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I wanted. I like having full control of my data. My next idea was to find a free hosting site and write some crazy PHP and set up a SQL database to set up comments.
But this got me thinking - how did sites handle comments before all this dynamic content was commonplace? A careful google search led me to an amazing blog post by Eduardo Boucas on how he solved this exact problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partying With Jekyll</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-11-12-partying-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 18:15:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-11-12-partying-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to fix this blog for a while now, and I decided in the process that I am awful at web design/programming. Haha, well, the first step to being kinda good at something is kinda sucking at something, right?
In my scouring of the internet I discovered that a lot of static blog sites used Jekyll to generate their site. At first, I figured it was nothing more than another insta-blog program where you just dump some content into a folder and it spits out a blog - but holy cow it is so much more than (and can be exactly) that. I&amp;rsquo;ve only scratched the surface of what it is capable of, since I don&amp;rsquo;t have many skills in the web developement category (yet).
I originally attempted to create my own Jekyll theme - and successfully recreated my original blog format. Unfortunately, I remembered (after spending a good deal of time working on it) that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like the look/feel of my original blog - and trashed it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>