<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sewing on Wsl Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/sewing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sewing on Wsl Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 07:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sewing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Daypack Ramblings</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-09-12-18lpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-09-12-18lpack/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, I get ideas that creep into my brain and won&amp;rsquo;t leave until I fully explore them. Back in February, while still enjoying the nice Arizona winters, I was hiking with my trusty old camelback. I&amp;rsquo;m fond of that pack, despite it&amp;rsquo;s many shortcomings. It has lots of fun places to attach things, and carries around 2L of water. It has zero storage capacity, although you can shove like maybe a protein bar in with the bladder&amp;hellip; but that&amp;rsquo;s it. So, if I want to bring my sketchbook, I usually shove the camelback in my larger Osprey daypack. The Osprey is a nice pack, lots of little pockets, but it&amp;rsquo;s aesthetically pleasing curves really limit what I can easily pack in there. I also use the Osprey for carrying (awkwardly) all my plein air painting gear - which, shouldnt take up all that much space but really stretches the limit for how much the Osprey can hold. Which, again, leaves room for maybe a protein bar.
      Snack capacity should be a very important part of backpack design considerations.
So the idea was born, could I design a small daypack that could carry a few snacks, sketching stuff, and my hydration bladder or all of my plein air painting stuff, tripod, and lunch?
One thing I noticed while making small practice packs for my daughter is that all the fun little pockets in commercial packs that are barely large enough for anything practical really eat into the total storage capacity - keeping a pack simple greatly increases it&amp;rsquo;s storage capacity, even if it technically has the same volume designation.
Also, while curves are pleasing, they really suck for packing things. With these ideas in mind I set out to make a prototype pack out of some cheap ripstop.
              Cool flap with zippered pocket, compression ties on the side to reduce size, daisy chains on back, drawstring collar&amp;hellip;Fancy right? Yeah too fancy&amp;hellip; but the size was right. The top flap was kinda wonky on the prototype, and honestly it was more of a hassle to deal with then it was worth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>