<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rambles on Wsl Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/rambles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rambles on Wsl Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rambles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Necromancy</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-10-23-necromancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-10-23-necromancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, my ambition to change the blog to a collection of posts about what I&amp;rsquo;m
currently doing apparently didn&amp;rsquo;t pan out for me posting more often. Time to
bring the blog back from the dead - some techno-necromancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happened in the three years and change since the last post? A lot,
actually. Ignoring the political landscape and all the nonsense from the COVID
times is hard, and probably why I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel motivated to write anything about
what I was doing with my personal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, my family and I relocated to small town coastal Oregon from the
sprawling metropolis of Phoenix, AZ. Work had an opportunity, I took a leap. The
Oregon coast is absolutely gorgeous - but we &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; quickly learned that it is
much nicer to visit (briefly) than to live. Work was challenging in many new and
unexpected ways (there&amp;rsquo;s too many trees here!). The three of us struggled to
adapt, and probably due to our stubborness we made it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrounded by the beauty of the coast, we tried to make the most out of living
there. On our 45 minute drives every week to the grocery store we&amp;rsquo;d pass dozens
of new and exciting hiking trails - so we spent a lot of time hiking and
exploring. We acquired a canoe, and took that out whenever we could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>